# **EDREIH ALDANA**

# ALDANA.EDREIH@GMAIL.COM • 936-239-7218 • HOUSTON, TX

## **SUMMARY**

Skilled DevOps Engineer with strong scripting skills, automation experience, and a deep understanding of designing and building software. Experienced with configuration management, deployment strategies, and troubleshooting distributed systems. Loves a good challenge, and strives daily in improving and evolving for the better.

## **SKILLS**

Infrastructure: Azure DevOps, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher

CI/CD, Test & Build Tools: Azure DevOps, Selenium, Apache JMeter, Postman, Ansible, Psake, Jenkins, SonarQube,

Chocolatey, jFrog Artifactory, ProGet

Version Control Software: Git, Azure DevOps, AWS CodeCommit, TFS, BitBucket, GitLab, GitHub

Scripting Languages: PowerShell, Bash, Python

Languages: C#, Ruby, Java, Javascript, node.js, Angular, PHP, Python, C++, HTML, CSS

Logging & Monitoring Tools: Splunk, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Grafana, Prometheus, Istio, SolarWinds Orion, ServicePulse

Operating Systems: Windows Server 2012/2016/2019, Windows Enterprise, Linux, macOS

Virtualization: VMWare vSphere, Citrix

**Databases:** SQL Server 2016/2019, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Oracle **Application & Web Servers:** IIS, Apache Web Server, Amazon Lightsail, ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core

IT Skills: Release management, CI/CD Automation, DevOps, requirements gathering, Scrum, Agile software development, Pull Request review, Quality Assurance, Test Automation, Server Administration, Maintenance/Patching, IT Support, Troubleshooting, Debugging, Network Administration, Data Backup and Recovery, Writing Technical Documentation

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# DEVOPS ENGINEER • ENTERPRISE PRODUCTS RELEASE MANAGEMENT TEAM

JAN 2020 - PRESENT

- Develop fully automated CI/CD pipelines for build, test, and release processes using Azure DevOps
- Architect automation processes that enable application deployments, configuration, scaling, and monitoring
- Leverage Kubernetes to orchestrate the deployment, scaling, and management of Docker containers
- Participate in on-call rotation and act as the point of contact for onshore and offshore teams to troubleshoot and resolve critical tasks in production environments
- Author detailed documentation as it pertains to release processes, CI/CD pipelines and internally developed tooling
- Implement open source logging and monitoring tools to support developer and QA teams. The tool allows for quick identification of bugs, mapping to ADO work items, alerting and notifications of future occurrences, and tracking regressions
- Develop scripts to deploy and configure Elasticsearch infrastructure at scale using Bash and PowerShell scripting
- Establish merging and pull request policies to support QA team sign off before merging to release branches
- Assist QA to ensure quality releases of various internally developed applications. Implement tooling to perform back-end, API, performance, regression, unit and integration testing
- Develop CI/CD pipelines to support test automation suites using Selenium web driver to execute automated testing of applications.

#### IT SPECIALIST • THE FUENTES FIRM, P.C.

**NOV 2018 - DEC 2019** 

- Managed technical support operations, troubleshoot issues and perform root cause analysis
- Served an instrumental role in company wide migration from legacy case management system (CMS) to new
   SharePoint system by setting up, migrating data, providing end-user training and documentation
- Automated legal document generation to streamline procedures and decrease Paralegal labor time. The system
  was designed to reduce human error and improve efficiency

- Managed and maintained Windows Server 2016 for Active Directory services and ensured high availability of critical data stored in network shares
- Developed client portal web application using AWS EC2 and custom WordPress site to provide clients with centralized access to their legal documents, contracts, and more
- Initiated IT policies designed to harden system security, including enhanced measures for password requirements and user access to company resources

# SYSTEM SUPPORT SPECIALIST - VARIAN MEDICAL SYSTEMS

FEB 2017 – OCT 2018

MOBIUS MEDICAL SYSTEMS • FEB 2017 - FEB 2018 • ACQUIRED BY VARIAN MEDICAL SYSTEMS FEB 2018

- Analyze, troubleshoot, and repair Linux servers used as medical appliances in Radiation Oncology departments worldwide
- Analyzed logs and stack traces to identify root cause, resolve issues, and document in knowledge base
- Corresponded with hospital IT departments to evaluate, setup product, and provide remote support through online ticketing system
- Assisted employees with set up of laptops, upgrades, and IT related issues
- Performed thorough validation testing and write essential documentation for new hardware components and software versions
- Design, implement, and administrate internal network, network shares, and systems

#### FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER • ALDANA DESIGNS

**MAY 2014 - DEC 2019** 

- Developed modern responsive websites using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL technologies
- Implemented project portal for clients to log in, check project status, and manage invoices
- Managed and configured custom WordPress and CMS installations
- Optimized client websites for top search engine rankings (SEO)
- Designed logo, branding, and prototypes using Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, and wireframe tools
- Managed and prioritize multiple projects with strict deadlines

# **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON – HOUSTON, TX

**FALL 2019** 

ASSOCIATE OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE SAN JACINTO COLLEGE – HOUSTON, TX

**MAY 2015**